<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frontend on dev_leelee.log</title>
    <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/tags/frontend/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frontend on dev_leelee.log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leeleelee3264.github.io/tags/frontend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(en) Divide layout in thymeleaf</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2020-10-25-front-thymeleaf-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2020-10-25-front-thymeleaf-layout/</guid>
      <description>Divide layout in thymeleaf. Index Trouble with not dividend html layout Divide layout Outro Trouble with not dividend html layout How do I feel about not divide html layout. Suffocating with 2000 line! At first, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the importance about splitting html and making layout. But when I saw 2000 line html files with so many duplicated code (mostly nav, header, side-bar) I felt like I should change my mind. In my opinion, the good things about such work are &amp;hellip; Pros in dividend html layout I don&amp;rsquo;t have to rewrite every header, footer, side-bar (AKA general frame of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(en) Implement Drag and Drop to upload file</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2020-10-08-front-dropdown-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2020-10-08-front-dropdown-file/</guid>
      <description>Implement Drag and Drop to upload file
Index
Intro Implement Drag and Drop Intro Upload file with more action! Few days ago, I had to make a function that is about taking excel file from client side and reading it to save to our database. I usually go as simple as possible in terms of HTML/CSS, but this time I did some research and work!
Instead of using basic file chose button, dragging a file and dropping in to a box. I was very happy when finishing these process because I thought it&amp;rsquo;s quite user friendly interface.
[Picture 1] Drag and Drop Implement Drag and Drop HTML &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;file-upload&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;button class=&amp;quot;file-upload-btn&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;button&amp;quot; onclick=&amp;quot;$(&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
