<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infra on leelee.log</title>
    <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/tags/infra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infra on leelee.log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leeleelee3264.github.io/tags/infra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] Nginx에 서브도메인 연결하기</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2023-03-25-subdomain-with-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2023-03-25-subdomain-with-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Nginx에서 서브도메인을 사용할 수 있도록 설정하는 방법을 알아본다. Index Intro Wildcard 적용한 Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt 인증서 발급 서브도메인 CNAME 등록 Nginx에 서브도메인 연결 Intro leelee.me 라는 도메인을 사서 쓰고 있었는데 jenkins를 설치하면서 jenki</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] 로드 밸런서란 무엇인가?</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2022-10-24-load-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2022-10-24-load-balancer/</guid>
      <description>이 포스트에서는 scale up, scale out, 트래픽과 함께 기초적인 로드 밸런서 지식을 다룬다. 끝에서는 로드 밸런스와 리버스 프록시를 비교한다. Index Intro: 터져버린 서버에 우아하게 대처하기 로드밸런서 (plus) 리버스 프록시 Intro: 터져버린 서버에 우아하게 대처하기</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] 인증서 (2/2): CA와 Chain of trust란 무엇인가?</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2022-08-27-digital-certificate-part-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2022-08-27-digital-certificate-part-final/</guid>
      <description>이 포스트에서는 인증서의 심화 개념인 Certificate Authority, root CA, CA bundle, chain of trust에 대해서 알아본다. Intro [디지털 인증서 쌩기초 파헤치기] 에서 인증서의 종류, PKI, X.509 와 같은 디지털 인증서의 기초에 대해서 알아봤다. 기초에 대해서 어느 정도 파악했다</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] 인증서 (1/2): Certificate, PKI, X.509란 무엇인가?</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2022-06-15-digital-certificate-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2022-06-15-digital-certificate-part-one/</guid>
      <description>이 포스트에서는 인증서의 기본 개념을 다룬다: CSR, SSL certificate, code signing certificate, FQDN, PKI, X.509 Index 인증서에 대해 잘못 알고 있던 점들 인증서의 종류 인증서와 관련된 개념 인증서에 대해 잘못 알고 있던 점들 인증서의 종류 적절하지 않은 인증서 분류 web에서 HTTPS 통신을 하</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] MySQL Study (5/5) - Backup</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-07-21-mysql-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-07-21-mysql-backup/</guid>
      <description>MySQL 백업에 대해 알아본다: Full backup, differential backup, incremental backup. Index 언제 DB 백업을 해야 하나? 백업 개념 MySQL의 백업 커맨드 Linux DB Migration 언제 DB 백업을 해야 하나? 백업의 용도 내가 실무에서 접할 수 있는 디비 백업의 용도는 2가지가 정도이다. (보관) 데이터 유실</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] MySQL Study (4/5) - Join &amp; Join Set</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-07-14-mysql-history-of-join-and-join-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-07-14-mysql-history-of-join-and-join-set/</guid>
      <description>MySQL join &amp;amp; join set에 대해서 알아본다: Inner join, left join, right join and full outer join. Index History of Join Join Set Reference 리뷰 후에 알게된 부분들 비등가 조인. Oracle에서는 지원을 하는데 Mysql이 지원을 하는지 모르겠다. 일반 조인이랑 비등가 조인 쿼리를 직접 짜서 결</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] MySQL Study (3/5) - String Function &amp; Referential Integrity</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-07-08-mysql-stringfunction-and-refrential-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-07-08-mysql-stringfunction-and-refrential-integrity/</guid>
      <description>MySQL string function에 대해서 알아본다: LENGTH(), RIGHT(), MID(), INSERT() and referential integrity: Restrict, No Action, Cascade, Set NULL. Index MySQL에서 String 함수 참조 무결정 소소한 하이디 SQL &amp;amp; markdown 팁 Reference 리뷰 후에 알게된 부분들 [Markdown 각주/미주 달기] 1 SUBSTRING_INDEX(문자열, 구</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] MySQL Study (2/5) - SQL &amp; key &amp; collation</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-06-30-mysql-sql-and-key-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-06-30-mysql-sql-and-key-collection/</guid>
      <description>MySQL SQL &amp;amp; key &amp;amp; collation에 대해서 알아본다, SQL: DML, DDL, DCL. Key: primary, foreign, super, candidate, alternative, surrogate. Collation: utf8, utf8mb4. Index Structured Query Language Key Collation Reference 리뷰 후에 알게된 부분들 Primary Key가 들어간 column 의 이름도 아닌 제약조건에 이름을 만드는 이유 주임님이 주신 의견: 기본키를 항상 하나의</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] MySQL Study (1/5) - Index</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-06-21-mysql-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-06-21-mysql-index/</guid>
      <description>MySQL Index에 대해서 알아본다: clustered, non-clustered structure and algorithm. B-Tree, R-Tree. Side effect of index. Index Clustered Index / Non-Clustered Index - Concept Clustered Index / Non-Clustered Index - Structure and Index algorithm Side effects of Indexes Related SQL Command with Indexes Reference 리뷰 후에 알게된 부분들 Non-Clustered Index가 여러 개 생성이 가능하지만 무제한으로 만들 수 있는 것은 아니다. 조회</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] 안 쓰는 노트북에 Ubuntu 설치하고 초기 설정하기</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-04-21-linux-server-init-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-04-21-linux-server-init-setting/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu 설치와 초기 설정 방법에 대해 알아본다. From basic: installation USB, network, static ip, SSH, user and sudoer to custom: prompt, build-essential, installation Maria DB. Index 리눅스 설치 초기 네트워크 설정 SSH 설정 사용자 설정 기타 설정 MariDB 설치/설정 리눅스 설치 리눅스 설치용 usb 리눅스를 설치하려면 설치용 usb를 먼저 만들</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] (en) Running Shiny server with Docker</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-01-30-build-server-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-01-30-build-server-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Handles running Shiny server with Docker. Index How I got into Docker Making Shiny Docker Troubleshooting with Network Reference How I got into Docker Docker make server infra as a code and we can share anywhere! Nightmare of installing library for Shiny I had wondered why many developers love docker so much for a while. A few days ago, I got a chance to install docker in my company&amp;rsquo;s test server. The thing is that we have shiny server written in R in the test server. I still remember I had to be though install a bunch of library to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] (en) Name convention of host and URL</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-01-13-linux-host-name-convention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-01-13-linux-host-name-convention/</guid>
      <description>Name Convention of Host and URL: Reserved characters and unsafe characters.
Index
Troubleshooting for Name Convention Name Convention Troubleshooting for Name Convention How I occurred the trouble Today, I had to be through very awful exception. There is an api server I have to send a request to update meta data. For performance issue, this server just cached meta data and uses it till updated. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s quite simple. Make request with RestTemplate in Spring boot.
This situation got started two days age. The server which contains api server moved to new ec2 machine, and it had new ip. So I have to send my request to the new ip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] (en) Write Shell script to deploy server and rotate log</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-01-05-linux-writing-shell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2021-01-05-linux-writing-shell-script/</guid>
      <description>Write shell script to deploy server and rotate log.
Index
Shell script to deploy server Shell script to rotate log (plus) /dev/null UPDATE VERSION OF SHELL SCRIPT WITH PASSWORD One month ago, I make this shell script with hard coded user password and I knew that was a bad idea. It is well known fact that leaving password somewhere or some files can be a huge problem with security later. So I decided to fix it.
How to request password in shell script
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 #!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Infra] (en) MySQL View and UNION/JOIN</title>
      <link>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2020-10-28-sql-view-union-join/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leeleelee3264.github.io/post/2020-10-28-sql-view-union-join/</guid>
      <description>Handles MySQL View and UNION/JOIN
Index
Intro View UNION/JOIN Intro Today, I faced my big mistake with new updated function which is made by me as well. The situation is something like this. We have a message service firing with multiple condition such as accomplish of today&amp;rsquo;s step count or tag reminder of today&amp;rsquo;s goal.
Table Design When we designed tables, we separate to act_message and goal_message. (Obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s design error. I was supposed to create one table for these two). And there is mp3 file table music_list because the message will be playing designated mp3 file when it gets fired.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
